Colonel Wilkerson, any thoughts on how our policy toward Israel does or does not benefit the United States?
Another great question.
Israel is probably a strategic liability of the first order for the United States.
I'm hoping that getting rid of Netanyahu and at the same time getting rid of Kushner and Pompeo and Trump
will alleviate the situation to the extent that we'll get a government in Israel,
maybe, that will see how dangerous it's future.
I said the other day Israel would not be a state in 20 years.
It'd be gone.
It certainly will not be a democracy.
It'll be an apartheid state and the world will just reject it as they did South Africa.
But I'm now saying it probably won't be a state.
It'll be gone.
Go back and read the report of the Joint Chiefs of Staff
when Truman was trying to decide whether or not to recognize Israel in 1947-48
and what to do about U.S. policy.
Completely no came from the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
Based on the fact there were 400 some odd million Arabs
and about at that time three, maybe four million Israelis and other things too.
And God, how prescient that report was.
Well, it's come true.
They are a strategic liability now.
The only strategic positive with regard to Israel is our relationship.
That is to say, there are a lot of American Jews
and there are a lot of connections with Israel.
That's the only positive aspect to our relationship.
Everything else is negative.
And if you want to go the full Monty,
you could say Israel is the most likely state in the world
to take the United States to Armageddon.
And I could paint you all sorts of ways we would do that
and the ways we would get there.
One would be the fact that for 40 plus years,
the military said, don't ever tell us to put a base in Israel.
Don't ever tell us that.
We will not comply.
Well, we just put a base in Israel.
There is a base in Israel flying the stars and stripes now.
In for penny, in for a pound.
Hezbollah shoots a rocket, hits that base.
Guess what?
The United States is with Israel when it goes to war with all of those Arabs
and maybe half the world combined.
Not a good deal.
So yes, Israel, I think, needs to be reined in
and it needs to be told in no uncertain terms,
you will change and you will change swiftly and effectively
or you can count your sugar daddy gone.
Not going to happen.
Yeah, but we do have that leverage if we were willing to use it,
but it takes political courage to do so.
After the first Gulf War, I watched H.W. Bush and Jim Baker
use the leverage gained in that war.
We restrained Israel.
We put people over there and said,
you will not respond to that Scud missile that just hit outside Tel Aviv
that Saddam Hussein shot at them
because we knew the whole coalition would fall apart if Israel joined the war.
That's how they are a strategic liability big time.
If we're not willing to use the leverage that we have like H.W. Bush did at that time
to bring about Oslo,
this relationship is going nowhere but downhill.